TUSHAR BATRA

4 +91**-**9464233537



Bangalore, India

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- https://tusharbatra.co.in/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/tushar0837/
- https://github.com/tushar0837

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with 8 years of experience designing, testing and developing software solutions. In-depth understanding of web technologies with focus on delivering innovative business solutions. Excels in fast-paced, high-energy and deadline-driven environment with willingness to take on additional tasks.

SKILLS

React

React Native

• Ruby On Rails

Python

AWS

• SQL

PostgreSQL

Google Cloud

Kafka

EXPERIENCE

01/2019 - Current Senior Software Engineer, Flyhomes, Remote, India

- Created dynamic landing pages for the marketing team, reducing several hours taken to create landing pages per campaign
- Led a small team of engineers to move the sales pipeline from a lead to deals based approach, helping the company effectively manage repeat customers
- Planned and worked from the ground up on scoring leads, helping the inside sales team to stay focused on the most important leads for the company
- Code owner of bookings and automated several parts of the tour booking process, reducing the time taken by internal teams from over 30 mins to under 5 mins
- Part of the team that worked on integrations with JustCall, Skedulo, Salesforce, Showing Time, WeChat, and MoEngage.
- Design and develop Postbox and Port micro-services for all the communication between Flyhomes and Third-Party services, or communication between two internal Flyhomes services. Integrated the Salesforce using the Postbox and Port services.
- Code owner for complex CRM integrations (Close, Copper) to read/write to the central database. These CRMs enable various teams to fulfill their daily job responsibilities
- Collaborated on integrating Flyhomes and ZeroDown data into a unified platform, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Worked with marketing and analytics team and led email and mobile notification campaigns, found bottle necks, started new campaigns to increase signup to lead conversion by 2 percent

01/2018 - 01/2019 Software Engineer, Think Future Technologies, Gurgaon, India

- Developed an Android app using the Ionic framework to track users' physical activities, displaying statistics and heat maps with various controls.
- Developed a hybrid Ionic 3 app for tenants and owners' communication
- Developed a React Web App Admin panel and a React Native mobile app from scratch for an international client.
- Analyzed project requirements and iterations, effectively estimated project deadlines by breaking the project into manageable modules.

• Analyzed project requirements and iterations, effectively estimated project deadlines by breaking the project into manageable modules.

11/2015 - 01/2018 Senior Analyst, Cappemini India Pvt. Ltd., Noida, India

- Structured the complete VBA code and independently handled complex calculations for a Driver Monitor module. Created ADB scripts for long-hour testing on IVI and worked with dSPACE for automation of cluster testing.
- Facilitated brainstorming sessions with project teams and provided substantial support to the Team Lead in creating work and analytical plans for effective project execution.
- Trained new and junior team members, supervising a team of three to carry out various ad hoc tasks.
- Developed a Daily Status portal for the execution team, utilizing Email Service and JavaScript to provide daily counts of tests being executed and their status to the Project Lead.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

07/2015

Bachelor of Technology Guru Nanak Dev University, Amritsar

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Awarded with Developer of the month in **Flyhomes**
- Awarded with Star of the month in Capgemini
- Awarded for a meritorious performance in Capgemini

LANGUAGES

| English: | Hindi: |
|-------------------|-------------------|
| Full Professional | Native/ Bilingual |
| Punjabi: | |
| Native/ Bilingual | |